[Unlocked.]
已开锁
Welcome back.
回来啦
Why are you still awake at this hour?
这么晚了怎么还没睡啊
[Locked.]
已关锁
I'm feeling a bit unsettled.
心里有点乱
I just dropped
刚刚
Weiyi off at her place.
把惟依送回家
How's Qi Yu doing?
齐郁怎么样啦
Not good.
也不太好
Ling Weiyi has been crying non-stop.
凌惟依一直在哭
I really don't know
我都不知道
how to comfort her.
该怎么安慰她
They've been together for so many years,
他们两个谈了这么多年
from college until now.
从大学时候到现在
They've had their ups and downs.
分分合合的
But no matter how much they cry or fight,
但是不管怎么哭怎么闹
I know that
我都知道
they both love each other deeply.
他们俩都是深爱着对方
That's true.
是啊
[I never imagined]
从来都没有想过
it would end up like this.
会有这样的一个结果
For dating,
谈恋爱吗
you just need to focus on the present.
只需要顾好眼前就好了
So everything feels simple.
所以一切都会很简单
And beautiful.
也都很美好
But once it comes to marriage,
但是一旦要步入婚姻
you have to think
就需要考虑
a lot about the future.
很多未来的事情
That's when various
所以会出现
real-life issues arise.
这样那样的现实问题
Seeing them like this,
看着他们俩这样
I can't help but feel
我就觉得
so lucky myself!
自己好幸福呀
Thank you, Mr. Ji.
谢谢你啊纪先生
Thank you for choosing me back then.
谢谢你当时选择了我
I also want to give myself some credit
我还要谢谢我自己
for agreeing to date you
当时
at that time.
答应了你
You really should be thanking yourself.
主要还是得谢谢你
[Xiaoning,]
小涂
[we just got word from Mr. Fu.]
小付总那边来消息了
[He's scheduled a meeting for tomorrow.]
约了明天见面
[We'll need to work late tonight]
今晚得加个班
[to refine the plan a bit.]
把方案再优化一下
[Let's meet at the office.]
我们行里见
[OK.]
好的
[I've prepared a few proposals.]
我做了几个方案
[Let's go over them together.]
咱们对一下
Ling Weiyi couldn't fall asleep.
凌惟依睡不着觉
She wants me to keep her company.
想让我过去陪陪她
Cool.
正好
I also need to go somewhere.
我也得出门一趟
Qi Yu
齐郁
wants to grab another drink with me.
他还想找我再喝一杯
What a coincidence.
巧了
Let me drive you there.
我先送你
No, I'm good.
不用 不用
I'll
我
call a driver,
叫代驾
or I can just take a taxi.
或者打车都行
Alright.
行
It's getting late.
都这么晚了
We should all take a taxi.
咱们都打车吧
Sounds good.
好
Let's go.
走
It's getting really late.
这都几点了
How come he is still not home?
还不回家
It's the middle of the night.
大半夜的
And Fanggang isn't home?
小赵哥出门了
He said he left behind
他说落了一份
an important document at the bank.
特别重要的资料在行里
He insisted on rushing back to get it.
非要着急忙慌地回去取
Your Mr. Ji
你们家纪行长
isn't home either, is he?
不会也没在家吧
Nope.
不在家
Looks like our opponent for tomorrow
看来咱明天的对手
is pretty obvious.
很明显了呀
These two guys
这两个男人
are quite childish.
幼稚
And petty.
小心眼
Isn't it just
不就是
competing for the same client?
竞争共同的客户吗
What's there to hide?
有什么好掖着藏着的
Seriously.
真是
Exactly.
就是
But when
那不过
we left home,
咱们俩出门的时候
we didn't tell them either, did we?
也没有如实相告吧
Nope.
那没有
When Fanggang left,
赵方刚走的时候
I was still at home,
我还在家
pretending to be asleep.
装睡觉呢
So he probably thinks
所以他现在肯定以为
I'm still lying in bed at home.
我在家躺着呢
And you just called him
那你刚才还说人家
petty.
小心眼
Double standards, huh?
双标啊
Business world is like a battlefield.
商场如战场吗
Every trick in the book is fair.
尔虞我诈
We're just pulling the same stun.
彼此彼此
Let's focus on the plan.
好好做方案
Come on.
快
Jing,
静姐呀
Be cautious.
小心提防
Mr. Zhao might be playing dumb.
小赵哥扮猪吃老虎
That guy?
就我们家那个
He's just a lightweight.
就那两下子
His tricks don't work on me.
跟我玩那小九九
But you should be extremely careful
倒是你们家纪行长
about your Mr. Ji.
你多提防着点
My Mr. Ji
我们家纪行长
is really quite cunning and shrewd.
真是老奸巨猾
He said that he was going to
不过刚才说
have a drink with
陪我闺蜜的男朋友
my bestie's boyfriend.
出去喝酒
I instantly figured him out.
我一下就猜到
Zhao Fanggang's
赵方刚在我这儿
stunts won't work on me whatsoever.
根本翻不出什么花来
I think that's about it.
我觉得差不多了
Come on.
来
Take a look.
你看一眼
I'm so sleepy.
困啊
I can't even remember how much
我都不记得今儿是
coffee I've had today.
喝得第几杯咖啡了
I heard that
据说
now Mr. Fu's got
现在小付总那边
only two banks left
就只剩两家银行
in the competition.
在比较了
Do you think we are up against
不会是咱们代瑞
another branch from Dairui?
窝里斗吧
That can't be right.
应该不是
When I left home,
我出门的时候
Ms. Rao had just fallen asleep.
饶总刚睡熟
Logically speaking,
按理说
for such a significant client meeting,
这么大的客户招呼见面
with her personality,
以她的性格
she definitely wouldn't sleep well.
肯定睡不安稳
If you're so curious,
你要是这么好奇
just give her a call.
打个电话问一下
Then you will find out what's going on.
不就都知道了
That wouldn't be appropriate.
那怎么行呢
She's pregnant now.
她现在怀着孩子
It's not easy for her to get a good sleep.
睡个踏实觉不容易
Hopefully, we're not competing with her.
不是最好 不是最好啊
After all, Mr. Fu is not someone
毕竟小付总这个人啊
I'd want my wife
我也不希望自己的老婆
to have too much contact with.
跟他多打交道
Why is that?
怎么说
I've heard that
我听说啊
when Mr. Fu
小付总
was abroad,
他在国外的时候
he was quite the playboy.
是一等一的花花公子
He changed his girlfriends
那换女朋友
like collecting stamps.
都跟集邮一样
With all different types of girls.
花里胡哨不带重样的
What do they call this type of guys
那个电视剧
in TV shows?
怎么叫这种人来着
A debauched playboy.
登徒浪荡子
Yeah.
对
Hey, come on,
要不说呀
you're still so nosy.
你还是这么八卦
We just need to focus on
我们只需要做好
our own duties.
自己的本职工作
As for the client's emotional preferences,
客户的情感癖好
let's not overanalyze.
不多做评价
Alright.
行
[He clearly left later than I did.]
他明明比我晚出门
[How did he manage to arrive first?]
怎么还早到了
[I can't let him get ahead of me.]
不行
[I have to meet Mr. Fu]
我必须在他之前
[before him.]
见到小付总
Hey, Xiaoning.
喂 筱柠
I accidentally
我刚才不小心
scratched my car
转弯的时候
while making a U-turn.
把车划了一下
[I think I saw your car nearby.]
我好像看见你的车了
You're around, right?
你也在附近吧
Could you come here and help me out?
你过来帮帮我呗
Is it serious?
严重吗
Where exactly are you?
你现在具体在哪儿啊
I'm right at
我就在
the entrance of Aijin.
爱锦园区的大门口
Got it.
行
I'm on my way.
那我现在过去啊
Just wait for me.
等我一下
OK.
好
Sorry.
抱歉啊
I'll be right back.
我一会儿过来
Hey,
师傅
excuse me,
麻烦问一下
has there been a
这附近刚刚有没有
minor collision around here?
发生一起剐蹭事故
Collision?
剐蹭
Yeah.
对
I haven't seen anything.
没见啊
Is it in here?
是咱们园区吗
Yes.
对
Just that white car.
就那辆白车
I really didn't see anything.
还真没看到
Alright.
行
I'll just go and check it out.
那我去看看
OK.
好
No problem.
没事
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Victory knows no rules.
兵不厌诈呀
Worrying only leads to confusion.
真是关心则乱
This is our president, Mr. Fu.
那位就是我们的付总
Mr. Fu.
付总
Nice to meet you, Mr. Fu.
付总您好
I'm from the Dairui Xingcheng branch.
我是代瑞星城分行的
My name is Tu Xiaoning,
客户经理
an account manager.
涂筱柠
Nice to meet you.
你好
Mr. Zhou, how do you
周会计
reduce the print size on this printer?
这打印机怎么缩印
I tried a few times, but it's not working.
我弄了半天不对啊
Let me take a look.
我看看
The printer's programming
这打印机的程序
has a bit of a problem.
出了点问题
I'll have the admin
我让那个行政部
find someone to fix it.
找个维修的来看看
Excuse me,
不用
allow me to take a look.
我来看看吧
This should be
这个应该是
a problem with the print size command.
缩印件指令出现了问题
Just a quick adjustment will do.
调一下就好了
Mr. Fu,
付总
how small do you want to
您想把营业执照
reduce the business license?
缩到多小
As long as it fits on an A4 paper.
能放到一张白纸上就行
Thank you!
谢谢你啊
It seems that Ms. Tu
看来涂经理
is very proactive in
在解决问题方面
solving problems.
有很强的主动性
I'm flattered.
没有
Practice makes perfect.
熟能生巧
We often help clients reduce
我们经常帮客户
the size of their business licenses.
缩小营业执照
So I've become familiar with it.
一来二去地就熟悉了
Please have a seat.
坐吧
Thank you.
谢谢
The last time I visited here,
上次来拜访您的时候
I noticed you're
发现您对咖啡
quite interested in coffee.
还是挺感兴趣的
There's a new hand-brewed coffee shop
这是我们公司
next to my office,
旁边新开的一家
and this is their product.
手冲咖啡
Please try it.
您先尝尝
Thanks.
谢谢
Ms. Tu, your keen observation skills
涂经理的观察能力
are quite impressive.
很强嘛
I've reviewed your proposal.
你的方案我看了
Using a letter of credit instead of a loan
用信用证代替贷款
is a solid approach.
思路很好
However, from what I understand,
但据我了解
a letter of credit
信用证好像
isn't always convenient.
也没那么方便
When it expires, it requires a discount
到期了还要押汇
or payment.
或代付
What's your take on this,
这一点
Ms. Tu?
涂经理怎么看
I suggested a letter of credit
我提信用证
mainly from
主要是从
a cost-saving perspective.
成本方面来考虑
[Youpin Tea]
我们优品茶叶
[is a significant taxpayer]
是星城的
[in Xingcheng.]
纳税大户
You have ample tax invoices.
我们有充足的税票
So if you opt for a letter of credit,
所以做信用证的话
the costs
我们的成本
will be considerably lower than
会比做贷款
taking a loan.
减少很多
Regarding the inconvenience you mentioned,
至于您说得不方便
our bank has already
我们银行也已经
upgraded
对信用证流程
the process.
进行了升级
It's now very efficient.
现在非常快捷
You can be assured of that.
这一点您可以放心
If I'm not mistaken,
如果我没猜错的话
you're likely planning to venture into
您接下来应该是想做
instant tea beverages next.
快消茶饮
In that case, the costs won't be low.
那线下费用就不会低
If you'd like to
如果您愿意
work with us,
跟我们合作的话
I can arrange
我可以申请
to waive your
减免您的
service fees
手续费
and acceptance fees.
还有承兑费
This way, you can save more money.
这样又能帮您省一笔钱
You really know how to
你还挺懂得
gauge people's feelings.
拿捏人心的啊
Not really.
不
This isn't about gauging feelings.
这不是拿捏人心
I simply
我是
prefer to approach things from
喜欢站在客户的角度上
the client's perspective.
考虑问题
Mr. President,
纪行长
are you here to meet a client?
来谈业务啊
About the client you mentioned earlier,
你之前提的那个客户
could he be...
该不会就
Didn't you tell me
你不是说
you had a collision?
有剐蹭吗
Shouldn't you have waited at the entrance?
不应该在门口等我
I got out of the car and checked.
我下车看了一下
It was nothing serious.
没什么大碍
Work takes priority.
还是工作要紧
So I went upstairs
我就上楼
to discuss business.
谈工作了
I apologize for that.
不好意思啊
I didn't mean to cause you any worry.
让你担心了
Making me worry is trivial,
让我担心是小
but regarding the client,
但是客户问题上
you keep saying I don't play by the book.
天天说我不讲武德
What about you?
那你呢
I have no choice, do I?
我不是没办法吗
Clients like Mr. Fu are certainly
像小付总这样的客户
sought after by many.
肯定很多人
Everyone is eager to present their plans.
拿着方案递过去吧
[It's about who makes the first impression.]
就看谁先见这一面
[If you leave a strong impression,]
留下深刻的印象
then no matter how good
那后面的人
the later presentations are,
讲得
it won't matter.
再多没有用
Because there's essentially nothing new.
没有新鲜感
After all, these proposals
毕竟这些方案
are pretty much the same.
都是大差不差的
Right?
是不是
Sounds quite candid.
听起来还挺坦荡的
Where's Mr. Zhao?
小赵哥呢
Why isn't he here?
他怎么不来呀
Is Mr. president
让纪行长
here to discuss business alone?
一个人来谈业务
Isn't Rao Jing also absent?
饶静不也没到吗
Jing is unwell.
静姐是生病了
She worked late last night
昨天晚上加班
and needs to go to the hospital today.
今天要去医院
Mr. Zhao is taking his wife
小赵哥是要陪他那个
to the hospital, who is feeling unwell
昨天晚上加班
after working late
今天身体不舒服的老婆
last night.
去医院
Got it.
好
I will
没什么事
be off then.
那我先走了啊
Just a friendly heads-up,
友情提示一下啊
Mr. Fu
小付总
seems to have a multinational
好像下午有一个
business meeting for this afternoon.
跨国业务要谈
I'm not sure if he'll have time
不知道今天有没有时间
to meet with Mr. Ji today.
留给纪行长
Regardless,
反正不管怎么样
I wish you
祝你
all the best.
一切顺利
This is only your first time
今天是第一次
meeting this Mr. Fu.
见这个小付总
Nothing is confirmed yet.
什么都没定呢
So don't get too excited.
别高兴太早啊
Bite me.
讨厌
Since Mr. Fu is so keen
既然小付总那边
to collaborate with us,
这么想跟咱合作啊
you should keep a close watch on this.
你就辛苦盯着点
Get the process wrapped up soon.
赶紧把那个流程给走完
I just got out of the hospital.
我这刚从医院出来
It's nothing serious.
没什么事
I'll be at the office shortly.
我马上就到行里
The order has already been placed.
单子都开了
You're really not going to get checked?
检查真的不做了
I'm perfectly fine,
我这也没什么事
so why waste the money?
浪费那钱干什么
Whoa,
好啊
Rao Jing,
饶静
were you trying to fool me?
耍我
Not at all.
哪儿有
But don't worry,
不过你放心
your president, Mr. Ji was also tricked.
你们纪行长也被耍了
So your supervisor, Mr. Ji
所以你们大哥
won't hold it against you.
说不着二哥
He won't blame you for this.
他不会怪你的
Dirty tricks
狼来了这招
won't work every time.
不可能回回都奏效的
This is the first major client
这是我进集安分行以后
that Yuheng assigned to me
老纪
after I joined the Jian branch.
交给我的第一个大客户
I'm not giving up.
我不会放弃的
Honey,
老公啊
let me ask you,
我问你
between Ji Yuheng and me,
我跟纪昱恒
who's your boss?
谁是你领导
In life, it's definitely you.
生活里肯定是你
But at work,
但工作上
it has to be him.
必须是老纪
Another question,
我再问你
we work hard.
我们努力地工作
Isn't it all for a better life?
是不是为了更好地生活
Yes.
是
Isn't it so that you can provide
是不是为了让我跟孩子
a better life for me and the kids?
有更好的日子
Absolutely.
是
What's your angle here?
你又有什么歪理
You see, my position is higher than yours.
你看我职级比你高
If I take on this project,
如果我接了这个项目
the commission and bonuses
佣金绩效
will definitely surpass yours.
是不是都比你高
This is very beneficial
这对于我们家庭而言
for our family.
十分的有利
Honey,
老婆
Mr. Ji
纪总呢
has already promised me the
已经把集安这边拓展部
manager position of the
拓展部经理的位置
business development department in Jian.
许给我了
Once I secure the project,
只要项目一拿下
I'll get promoted right away.
我立马升职
At that point,
到时候
I'll be earning just as much as you,
我钱拿得不比你差
and I'll be one level higher.
还升了一级
So it sounds like
这么听起来
I'm the one getting the better deal here.
还是我这边更划算
Ms. Rao,
饶总
you've been clever all your life,
枉你聪明一世
but you still miscalculated one thing.
还是算少了一步
But that's alright.
但是没关系
Don't take it to heart.
你也别生气
We're all doing this for the family.
我们都是为了家庭嘛
Hands off!
放手
Honey,
老婆
what would you like to eat? I'm buying.
你想吃什么我带你去
Don't be upset, hon.
老婆你别生气嘛
Getting angry can affect the baby.
你生气容易动了胎气
You two haven't seen each other
你们俩也挺长时间
for quite some time, right?
没见了吧
Do you plan to keep dragging this out?
打算一直这么拖着呀
I've blown through a few thousand
我早就把我俩
we had saved up.
攒那几千块钱花光了
How could we even meet?
怎么见啊
Besides,
况且
he hasn't reached out to me either.
他也没联系我
If you want him to apologize,
你要是想让他道歉的话
I can go talk to him.
我可以去找他呀
Never mind.
算了
This time, it's different.
这次啊跟之前都不一样
I've got a hunch
我有预感
that even if we meet and make amends,
就算我们见了面合好了
it won't address the core issues.
也没办法解决根本问题
We'll inevitably end up back here.
迟早会走到这一步的
I really can't wrap my head around this.
我其实就想不明白啊
Why is it that for others,
你说为什么在别人那儿
not having money is a problem,
没钱是个问题
but for me, having money
在我这儿有钱
becomes a problem instead?
反而还成问题了呀
Luxury cars,
豪车
a mansion in downtown,
市中心的大房子
and endless credit cards...
刷不完的信用卡
I've got all of these.
这些我都有
I don't feel
我也没觉得
there's any issue at all.
有什么问题啊
Ordinary people
你说普通人
work hard their entire lives.
辛辛苦苦奋斗一辈子
Isn't it all to
不就是为了
achieve a life like this?
过上这样的生活吗
I'm living it now,
我现在过上了
yet I still have to reflect on myself.
我还得反思
And change myself.
改变我自己
What nonsense is all this?
你说这都是什么道理啊
And him?
他呢
He can't just go with the flow
做不到顺其自然地
and live
跟着我
comfortably in my world.
在我的舒适圈生活
I thought to myself,
我就想着
alright then.
行
I'll make an effort
我努力地
to get closer to his world.
去靠近他的舒适圈
But I soon realized that
却发现
it seems impossible.
好像也没有办法
Scraping by just to make ends meet,
紧紧巴巴地攒钱过日子
buying a house in the suburbs,
买个郊区的房子
commuting two hours every day,
每天通勤俩小时
and I can't even enjoy a cake on weekends.
周末连个蛋糕都吃不到
I really can't live like that.
这样的日子我真过不了
Neither of you is wrong.
你们俩没有谁对谁错
It's fundamentally about how
是从根本上
you both perceive money.
你们俩对钱的认知
Yours are different.
就不一样
Your needs for life are also different.
对日子的需求也不一样
These differences didn't surface when you
这些都是在上大学
were in college or during the
跟热恋的时候
early days of your relationship.
体现不出来的
If you both want to
那你们俩想要
move forward,
往前再走一步的话
these issues
这些问题
will gradually
就会慢慢地
come to the forefront.
全都体现出来
That's true.
是啊
We've both
我们俩
tried our best to make it work.
也都努力过了
Hey, Tingting.
喂 亭亭
[Xiaoning,]
小涂姐
[do you have any plans this afternoon?]
你下午有事吗
I have a client who just
我这边有个客户
asked me to meet all of a sudden.
临时约我过去聊一聊
He insisted that we must meet today.
说今天务必见一面
But I've already scheduled
可我已经
an appointment with another client.
跟另一个客户约好了
I really can't meet him.
实在排不开
Xiaoning...
小涂姐
That's alright.
没事
How about this:
那要不
just send me the
你把那个
files of this client,
客户的资料发给我
and the location of your meeting.
还有你们约的地点
I will see him in your stead shortly.
我一会儿帮你走一趟
[Thank you so much, Xiaoning!]
太谢谢你了小涂姐
[I'll send them to you right away.]
我这就发给你
No problem.
不用谢
Go on.
快去吧
Don't worry about me!
别担心我啦
I'll be
一会儿
heading back to work as well.
我也要回去上班喽
Huihuang Advertising?
晖煌广告
I'm going.
我去了啊
If you're feeling down,
你要是心情不好啊
text me on WeChat.
微信留言给我
Don't worry about me.
放心吧
Help me clean up, OK?
帮我收一下
Sure.
好嘞
[Shouldn't it be called "Huihuang"?] [*another character in mandarin]
不是应该叫辉煌吗
[Could it be that]
莫不是
[the boss' name contains]
老板的名字里
[the character "Hui"?]
有个晖字
May I ask,
麻烦问一下
what is your boss' surname?
咱们老板贵姓啊
Our boss' surname is Yu.
我们老板姓余
I read the profile
我有查过
of your company.
咱们公司的资料
He is neither the legal representative
老板既不是法人
nor a stakeholder.
也不是股东啊
The legal representative is his mother,
法人是他老妈
and the stakeholder is his wife.
股东是他老婆
Technically, he doesn't hold
他在明面上啊
any official position.
什么都没有体现
No wonder.
怪不得
You're from the bank, right?
银行的是吧
Sorry, I was running late.
真不好意思
I urgently need a small loan,
我着急用一笔小额贷
so I thought
所以想着
I'd make some time this afternoon
今天下午腾出空来
to meet you.
赶紧来见一见
This is quite last-minute, huh?
是挺仓促的啊
No problem, Mr. Yu.
余总您客气了
I'm Tu Xiaoning,
我是代瑞的
an account manager for Dairui.
客户经理涂筱柠
Here's my business card.
这是我的名片
[Tingting and I are colleagues.]
我跟亭亭是同事
[Today, we'll just]
今天呢我们先
[have a brief discussion.]
简单地聊一下
If you have
日后如果您有
further needs in the future,
进一步的需求
Tingting will be your main contact.
还是亭亭来跟您对接
Tu Xiaoning?
涂筱柠
You went to Xincai High School,
你高中是新才中学的
class 12, right?
十二班
Yeah.
对
So it's really you, Tu Xiaoning!
果然是你啊涂筱柠
It's me!
我呀
Don't you remember?
你不记得了吗
Back in high school,
你上高中那会儿
after we finished evening classes,
下晚自习放学的时候
you fell off your bike
骑自行车
into a sewer.
陷进下水道口给摔了
Yu Hui?
余晖
Yes, that's me!
对啊就是我
Come on, have a seat!
快坐 快坐 快坐
Thanks.
谢谢
OK,
那个
could you grab some good tea
去我后备厢里
from my trunk?
拿上好的茶叶
I'd like to catch up
我和我的老同学
with my classmate.
叙叙旧
Get the best one!
要最好的
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
No problem.
没事
So you're working at the bank now?
你现在是在银行上班啊
Yes, I am,
对
as an account manager.
客户经理
Funny coincidence, I'm here to discuss
也是巧了
a business opportunity with Mr. Yu.
营销到余总您头上来了
Please don't tease me.
你可别埋汰我了
This "Mr. Yu" is really no big deal.
我算哪门子余总啊
I just didn't do well in school,
我就是当年成绩不好
and never received a good education.
学历还差
So I
就
just opened a small company.
随便开了家小公司
[Doing my own stuff.]
自己做做
[I originally thought]
本来想着
[I'd consult the bank]
咨询下银行
about small loans.
关于小额贷的事情
Now that you're here,
你这一来
I won't need anyone else.
我也不问别人了
I'll just come to you.
我就找你
Consider this
就当是当年
my apology for
顽劣不懂事
being a brat back then
还欺负你
and bullying you.
跟你道个歉
It's been so many years.
当年都过去这么多年了
Let's put it all behind us.
我们不要再提了吧
We were
都是小时候
just kids back then.
小孩子都不懂事的
Besides, it was my fault too.
再说也怪我自己
Throwing a basketball at you was wrong.
拿篮球砸你也是我不对
I apologize from the bottom of my heart.
我是真心跟你道歉的
Looking back.
回想起当年的自己
I was really a jerk and immature.
真的是又混蛋又不懂事
I can't believe I used to bully
欺负女同学这种事情
my female classmates.
都做得出来
I was a monster!
就是个小畜生
That's exaggerated.
没那么严重
I remember
记得当年我整你的时候
the famous handsome Ji Yuheng
咱们的级草纪昱恒
stood up
还挺身而出
and stopped me
把我给拦下了
from making serious mistakes.
没让我犯更大的错误
By the way,
对了
things between you two
你俩关系
got special, huh?
后来挺那啥的吧
Who?
谁俩
What special?
哪啥了
Nothing.
没啥 没啥
Seeing you
我这又见到你了
reminds me of another old friend.
想起另外一个老同学
It's been ten years.
这一晃十年也过去了
I tell you, I'm a very
我跟你说我这个人
gregarious person.
就特别爱热闹
I've always wanted to throw a party
我一直想组一个局啊
and invite all the classmates
把咱留在星城的同学
in the city
全部给叫过来
for a good chat.
吃吃喝喝聊聊天
Right.
对了
Can I have your WeChat number?
咱们加个微信呗
Yes.
好
If I really have a party,
然后到时候我组个局
you have to be there.
你可得赏脸来啊
I'll scan it.
我扫您
Okay.
好
Here.
来
Tingting.
亭亭
You've got the contract?
客户谈下来了
What a small world.
说来也巧
That guy happens to be
那个人正好是
my classmate from high school.
我高中同学
We've made the deal.
我跟他说好了
You can take care of
具体的呢还是
the paperwork and credit.
跟你走流程吧
He'll contact you in a couple days.
过两天就会联系你了
Thank you, Xiaoning.
谢谢你小涂姐
We can split the credit.
等绩效下来了我跟你分
Alright.
行
Thank you.
那我就不客气了
[Xiaoning!]
小涂 小涂 小涂
Well,
那个
Mr. Fu from Youpin is here.
优品的付总来了
He's waiting for you.
等你半天了
The younger Fu?
小付总啊
Yes.
对
He's here in person?
亲自过来了
Yes. Get over there.
是你抓点紧
Okay, okay.
好 好 好
You can do this.
加油
Ms. Tu.
涂经理
My apology, Mr. Fu.
不好意思啊付总
I just had to
我今天临时有点事
go out for a while.
出去了不在行里
Sorry for the wait.
让您久等了
It's okay, Ms. Tu.
没关系涂经理
I didn't make the appointment either.
是我来得临时了
I've read your
我看了你那
financing proposal.
具体的融资方案
I think the details must be
我觉得有些细节
decided face to face.
还是当面聊一下比较好
I happen to be near on business.
正好在这附近办事
So here I am.
就过来了
Thank you, Ms. Tu.
辛苦你了涂经理
You revised the plan
上次聊完之后
immediately after our last chat.
你这么快就改了方案
I'm looking forward to our
希望我们未来
future cooperation.
合作愉快
So,
那
let's go through it one by one.
我们就一条一条得来
Okay.
好的
Why don't you sit over here?
涂经理要不你坐这边吧
It's more convenient.
我们看也方便点
Okay.
好
You can take a look at this.
您先看一下吧
This one.
这条
Last time
上次呢
we mentioned
我们只是提到了
the FMCG tea drinks.
快消茶饮
As for specific
但是具体的公司
in-house names and sizes,
内部的名目和计划规模
I need you
还是要等您
to give me
再给我寄一些
more detailed
比较详细的
information
资料
before I can add.
我才能再补充
So I can't add this one
所以这条
before I have...
我还是等您的
...more information
等您的资料
from you.
发给我以后再说吧
Why so nervous?
怎么了这么紧张
Relax.
放轻松点
It's okay.
没有
I'm fine.
没什么
I'll leave you to it.
您接着看
Are you a local, Ms. Tu?
涂小姐是本地人啊
You can call me Xiaoning, Mr. Fu.
付总您叫我小涂就行
I am a local.
我是本地人
I heard
听说
you came back from studying abroad
您是从国外留学回来
for your doctorate.
读的博士
I've been a PhD student for two years,
读了两年博以后
because I didn't want to come back
因为不想回来
to take over the family business.
继承家业嘛
To stall for time,
为了多逃避段时间
I had to go on with my degree.
所以只能继续往后读
Are you thinking,
你是不是在想
"He came back
最后我不还是回来
to take over in the end."
继承家业了
It's not my choice.
没办法
Not everything
有钱人
goes smoothly for the rich.
也不是事事能够顺心的
Right.
也是
[I want to know]
也不知道
[if Weiyi is feeling better.]
惟依心情好些了没有
What's on your mind?
想什么呢
Nothing.
没什么
Here's the elevator.
电梯到了
Have a nice day.
您慢走
Ms. Tu.
涂经理
No need for seeing me off.
不用送了
We'll meet again soon.
我们很快还会再见的
Well, take care.
那您慢走
What are you looking at?
看什么呢
Xiaoning.
小涂姐
It's for you.
送你的
For me?
送我的
Open it up.
快打开看看
[Yes.]
对
[It's for you.]
送你的
It's from Mr. Fu.
刚才那个小付总
I take it here
放在会议室
from the conference room.
我就给你拿出来了
He must have seen you
肯定是看你
working too hard lately.
最近太辛苦了
[Ms. Tu, please take
涂经理一点心意
[this small gift.]
请你收下
This is
这一套
expensive.
不便宜呢
Xiaoning.
小涂姐
This...
这
Hello?
喂
Hello, Mr. Fu.
喂 付总
How's the gift?
怎么样
You like it?
礼物喜欢吗
I'm sorry,
不好意思啊
but it's too expensive for me
这个礼物有点贵重
to take it.
我不能收
How about this?
是这样
If it's convenient for you,
您看您方便
should I send it to you now
我现在给您送过去呢
or by courier?
还是给您快递过去
[If you really want to thank me,]
你要是真感谢我
[buy me dinner.]
那就请我吃饭吧
[We'd better set a time now.]
择日不如撞日
[How about tonight?]
今晚如何
Okay.
行
So,
那
which restaurant do you like?
您想吃哪家餐厅
There's a nice Japanese restaurant
你们银行附近
near your bank.
有家日料还不错
Okay.
好
I'll see you at 7:00 p.m.
那就晚上七点
At Kikukawa.
我们菊川见
Okay.
行
See you tonight.
晚上见
Bye.
拜拜
I'll give it back
一会儿给他送过去
to him later.
就好了
Go back to your work.
散了吧
Be careful.
你慢点啊
Thank you for helping me
辛苦你了啊
with the business dinner
吐成这样
despite your pregnancy sickness.
还陪我出来应酬
It's okay.
说什么呢
In public, I'm your superior.
于公我是你的领导
This is my job.
这是我的工作
In private,
于私
I'm your mentor.
我是你的师父
Just in case
万一待会儿那个什么
that Mr. Fu
小付总
tries to do something
真的对你有什么想法
improper to you.
对你虎视眈眈的
I can't stand by
我能看你自己
while you're in danger.
身处险境吗
Thank you so much.
谢谢师父
Let's go.
走
Come on in.
进
Be careful.
姐你慢点啊
Good evening.
您好
Mr. Fu.
付总
Let me introduce.
给您介绍一下
This is
这是我们
Ms. Rao from S1 of BDD,
拓展一部的饶总
my higher authority.
我的顶头上司
Nice to meet you, Ms. Rao.
饶总您好
Nice to meet you, Mr. Fu.
久仰了付总
You didn't
你今天
tell me in advance.
没有提前跟我打招呼
So the room I booked
所以我订的这个包间
probably won't seat three.
可能坐不下三个人
Well, then...
那咱们就
I think...
我觉得
What a coincidence.
那正好
I booked a room for four.
我订了一个四人间
How about we eat together?
我们一起啊
Are you okay, Jing?
姐怎么样
Sorry.
不好意思啊
If you're
要是
really uncomfortable,
实在难受的话
you can go home.
姐你先回去吧
Sorry, Mr. Fu.
不好意思啊付总
I didn't expect
没想到
pregnancy can be
怀个孕给自己
such a mess.
怀这么狼狈
It's okay, Jing.
没事静姐
You don't have to stay if you're not well.
要是不舒服就先回去
Mr. Fu
付总
is magnanimous.
不是小心眼的人
He can understand.
他能理解
I'm here now.
正好我在
I won't
小涂
let Xiaoning drink too much.
我不会让她贪杯
Don't worry.
放心吧
Okay.
那也行
Xiaoning,
那筱柠
please
今天
take care of Mr. Fu.
付总就拜托你了啊
I'm so sorry, Mr. Fu.
实在不好意思付总
I'll buy you dinner next time.
下次我一定请您吃饭
It's okay.
理解 理解
I'm really sorry.
实在不好意思
I'll leave you then.
那我就先走了
I'll see you off.
我送你
No need.
不用
Stay.
你坐
Okay.
好
Be safe, then.
那注意安全啊
I'm off.
走了
Make yourselves at home.
别拘谨啊
Let's talk about it over dinner.
咱们边吃边聊
Okay.
好
Let's eat.
吃吧
Try this.
尝尝这个
Thank you.
谢谢啊
I've heard about
我听过你们
the proposal of Ji'an branch.
集安分行的方案
Didn't expect
没想到
the president is so young.
行长这么年轻
I've stayed abroad too long
我在国外待久了
to know much
对这些
about the situation.
没什么概念
But a lot of talent has emerged
不过国内这几年
at home in the last few years.
确实出现了不少人才
I dare not believe that
还真是没想到
Mr. Fu is impressed with
付总对于我们
the proposal
集安分行的方案
at Ji'an branch.
还有印象
From the written proposal,
硬件条件来讲
Dairui is offering
代瑞给出的条件应该是
the best deal
全星城
of any bank in town.
所有银行里最好的
And
那
our branch should be
我们分行呢
the most suitable for Mr. Fu
操作方式上
in terms of the way it operates.
应该是最适合付总的
Aren't you so clever?
又耍小心思了
Sorry.
不好意思
Too much wasabi.
芥末放太多了
Sorry. Sorry.
不好意思 不好意思
-Here. -Sorry.
这个给你 不好意思
Sorry.
不好意思
This one's for you.
这个口味适合你
Looks like you
看来纪行长
knows your colleagues well.
对自己的同事很了解啊
Know people well and appoint them well.
知人善任
No wonder you're excellent in business.
怪不得事业做得这么好
Actually, I don't know many people.
其实我了解的人不多
Xiaoning
不过筱柠
is an exception.
确实算一个
Though you know her,
了解
you still don't know
不还是不知道
what tricks she used
我们涂经理在方案里
in the proposal.
使了什么小花招
I don't need to know.
那是因为没有必要
Dairui is offering
代瑞给出的条件
the best deal in town.
是全星城最好的
But all things being equal,
不过在同等条件之下
the proposal that Ji'an can offer
集安分行能给出的方案
is the best in all branches of Dairui.
就是全代瑞最好的
So,
纪总给出的是
what's your offer?
什么条件啊
Mr. Fu has read the proposal.
付总看过方案
He knows.
他肯定都知道
He did make a better offer
他们的条件
than you did.
确实比你们好
But in my opinion,
不过在我看来
banks and corporations
银企合作
work together, just like normal business.
就像做生意一样
Fate and
需要看缘分
friendship matter.
还有情分
Both of them
这两者
are indispensable.
缺一不可
[You're correct.]
付总说得没错
[Here's a toast to you.]
这杯酒我敬您
Long-term cooperation is based
无论做什么生意
on the exchange of benefits
长远的合作
and mutual trust
看的是利益交换
in all kinds of business.
和彼此的信任
Mutual Benefits
有来有往
for a Win-Win situation.
才能达到共赢
Don't you think so?
是吧筱柠
We both toast to you.
一起吧
It's against
在银行
our bank's code.
这是违规的
Thank you,
谢谢您的好意
but I really can't take it.
我真的不能收
So I give it back to you.
还给您付总
It's okay.
没关系
There's still time.
以后还有机会
Mr. Ji,
那行纪行长
I'll leave now.
我先走一步
Looking forward to our cooperation.
期待合作
So?
那
Going back to work this late?
这么晚了还要回去加班
I'm going home.
回家
I take my car,
你坐你的车
you take yours.
我坐我的车
Don't follow.
不许跟着我啊
Mr. Ji.
纪行长
You were blatantly
你在我面前
stealing clients
真是毫不掩饰地
from me.
抢客户啊
Wasn't it too much?
太过分了吧
I just ran into you
我呢今天只是
and had a
碰巧遇到
casual chat with him.
随便跟他聊聊天而已
Besides, if I hadn't been there,
再说了要是我不在的话
you would
饶静
have suffered from
不舒服提前走了
Mr. Fu's gaze
你一个人
after Rao Jing feeling
还不得被那个小付总
uncomfortable and leaving.
给盯出个窟窿来啊
He's just my client.
他只是我的客户
The luxury gift.
那送高档礼物
Private room for only two.
订双人包间
I don't think this Mr. Fu was
看来这个小付总
satisfied just to be your client.
不是只想做你的客户啊
Xiaoning.
小涂
Are you jealous?
吃醋啦
Yeah.
是
But I care more about your safety.
但是我更在意你的安全
Don't use jealousy as a cover.
不要拿吃醋当幌子
Don't think I'm going to
不要以为这样
let my guard down
我就对你
because of
掉以轻心
your affection.
放松警惕
You can always let your guard down on me.
你不用对我放松警惕
But not
但是不能对别人
on others.
掉以轻心
Bank lenders
银行放贷啊
must have their own bottom line.
是要有自己底线的
We need to have
我们要对客户
risk control over our clients,
有一个风险控制
while at the same time
同时自己
taking the initiative ourselves.
要尽量掌握主动权
Once we have some
一旦在前期
concessions at the beginning,
有一些模糊的退让
the clients will take control
就会让对方变本加厉地
and ask more.
掌握局势
It's going to be very hard
到时候你要再想
to regain control again
强势起来
at that time.
可就太难了
Mr. Ji,
纪总
thanks for reminding me.
教育的是
Losing one or two clients
失去一两个客户呢
won't put Dairui out of business,
代瑞不会倒闭
nor let it go bankrupt.
银行不会破产
But for me,
但是对于我
a little
一个小小的
account manager,
客户经理来说
it means a lot more.
意义可就不一样了
Each client is a result of
这每一个客户
patient communication,
可都是我耐心沟通
careful management,
细心经营
and hard work of mine.
最后努力争取来的
I won't let anyone
我不允许任何人
take them from me.
去打他们的主意
But you're mine.
但你是我的人
I won't let anyone
我不能让任何人
take you from me.
打你的主意
Don't worry.
你放心吧
I'm not a
我又不是
damsel in distress
对待那些人
when it comes to them,
都是毫无防备的傻白甜
nor a cunning woman using
也不是心机到会拿感情
intimacy to get what I want,
去谈工作的人
nor a coward giving up
更不是因为一些
a client because of
捕风捉影的猜测
baseless gossip.
就放弃一个客户的人
I'm a grown-up with a brain.
我是有脑子的成年人
I know what to do when facing
身在感情中呢
unwanted intimacy.
我懂得自觉
Otherwise, I wouldn't have asked Jing
要不然我也不会让静姐
to come with me.
跟着我一起去
Is that
这些
a relief for you?
你总该放心了吧
Okay.
好
Did you tell Rao Jing
年假的事情
to take your annual leave?
你跟饶静说了吗
When is your vacation?
什么时候有时间
I'll make the plans.
我来安排
Around the Mid-Autumn Festival, I guess.
中秋节前后吧
Okay.
好
How did you know we were
我们今天在这儿吃饭
having dinner there today?
你怎么知道的
Who told you?
谁跟你说的
No comment?
不回答
Okay.
好
Question two.
第二个问题
What's your proposal?
你们的方案是什么呀
We're in the same bank.
大家都在一家银行
There shouldn't be too much
给出的条件
of a difference in the terms offered.
应该没什么太大差别吧
You have to answer
两个问题
one of these two questions.
选一个回答
Choose.
快选
It's Li Xiang.
李想
Traitor.
敌人在内部
How dare him.
太可恶了
[Mr. Ji.]
纪先生
[Would it be convenient tomorrow]
明天方便把戒指
[to bring the ring and]
和您说的信物娃娃
[the token doll you mentioned?]
一起带来吗
[We'll be working]
我们会配合着
[with some special setups.]
做一些特殊的布置
[Okay.]
好
Xiaoning.
小涂姐
You've got good fortune.
撞上大款运了
Your gifts are getting even more lavish.
过一天还升一档呢
Lang.
小元
How can you say that?
造次了啊
Xiaoning has
小涂已经
returned the gift yesterday.
把昨天礼物送回去了
We're not allowed
咱们不允许
to take gifts from clients.
收客户的礼物
Then
那
who gave her this gift?
这是谁送的呀
It must be her boyfriend.
那肯定是人家男朋友啦
Li Xiang.
李想哥
Should I
我要不要
hold it
拿着这个东西
with a surprised face,
表现出非常惊喜的样子
and you take a picture of me
让你拍张照片
as proof of merit?
拿去邀功啊
Of course, I...
没问题 拍
Mr. Ji told you?
纪总把我给卖了
Well, I...
那 我
You're really going to take the pic?
你还真要拍啊
I may tell Jing that
小心我到静姐那儿
you're a traitor.
说你吃里扒外
[I,]
我
no,
不是
Xiaoning,
小涂啊
don't tell Ms. Jing!
你千万别跟静姐说
She would kill me!
她不得把我给嘎了呀
I know.
我知道
I'm always on Section One's side
在大是大非上
when it comes to principles.
我的心都在拓展一部
I swear I'd never betray.
我发誓绝对不会背叛的
Yeah, I know.
好 我知道
But in the future,
但是以后
if you have to be a traitor,
你要叛变
you can work for me.
在我这边
Okay.
好
What are you looking at?
看啥呢散了
Go back to your work!
散 散
[Is this the strange]
这就是男人
[competitive nature of men?]
奇怪的好胜心吗
[Do you like it?]
喜欢吗
Naive.
幼稚
Hello, Xiaoning.
喂 筱柠
Are you busy now?
还在忙吗
Do you want to have lunch together?
中午要不要一块吃饭啊
The business with Mr. Fu
由于我跟小付总那边
works very well,
推进得比较快
[so I plan to]
所以呢
[go to see him this afternoon]
下午我要去趟
[in his office]
小付总公司
to check with the proposal.
跟他聊一下业务
Sorry I can't join you for lunch.
中午就不能跟你吃啦
You have
你自己
a light lunch.
随便垫点
We'll have dinner together.
晚上一起吃
Come on in.
进
Time for takeout.
外卖时间到
Two takeouts for free delivery.
一起下单省个配送费
Any progress
小付总那边
this morning with Mr. Fu?
上午有什么说法吗
I contacted him this morning.
我上午跟他们联系了
He's still interested
他对我们的利率
in our rates.
还是感兴趣的
I'll keep an eye on it this afternoon.
我下午继续盯一下
You get some rest
今天下午啊
this afternoon.
你好好休息休息
Leave it to me.
我过去
I'll skip lunch.
中午饭我也不吃了
Don't skip lunch!
饭还是得吃的
You've lost weight lately.
我感觉你都瘦了最近
Mr. Zhou.
周会计
I'll be there in ten minutes.
我还有十分钟就到了
[Right.]
好的
[Drive carefully then.]
那您开车小心一点
I'll meet you at the gate.
一会儿我在大门口接您
You'll be with us all day long
今天实地走访
on today's field trip, won't you?
您全程会跟着对吧
[Yes.]
对是的
Okay, see you.
好一会儿见
[See you.]
好的一会儿见
Ms. Tu.
涂经理
Here's the revised contract.
这是我们改好的合同
Thank you.
谢谢
If you have no
如果小付总
further questions,
没有其他问题的话
I'll go back and get ready to
我就先回去整理一下
formalize the contract.
准备正式走合同
I'll see you tomorrow for a signature.
明天找您来签字
Is that okay with you?
您觉得怎么样
Mr. Zhou.
周会计
It's out of tea.
水没了
Okay.
好的
Thank you.
谢谢
Check it.
看看
To be honest,
不瞒你说
it's not easy to
让一个喜欢咖啡的人
get a coffee lover
经营茶厂
to run a tea factory.
确实不容易
[I'm sure you've heard about it.]
相信你也有所耳闻
[Until I returned home, Youpin]
优品茶叶在我回国之前
[had been run by my brother-in-law.]
一直是由我姐夫把持
It wasn't until recently
直到近期
that it was returned to me
才在我父亲的授意下
at the behest of my father.
交回到我手上
My brother-in-law
我姐夫呢
took a lot of old staff
走的时候带走了
with him when he left,
许多自己人
including our
包括做了
veteran financier.
很多年的老财务
Youpin needs to expand,
但优品茶叶
but it needs money first,
需要扩大经营
and someone
需要钱
to take care of finance.
更需要人来管钱
I need someone I can trust,
我需要一个信得过的人
with Mr. Zhou,
来跟周会计一起
to keep the finance department afloat.
把财务部撑下去
Xiaoning,
筱柠
I think you're perfect for it.
我觉得你很合适
I did see
我确实看到了
the generous
小付总
offer you have
给出的条件
made me.
很丰厚
But
但是
I do my current job
对于我来说现在的工作
not just for salary.
不只是为了赚钱
I love it.
我是真心喜欢
So I have to apologize.
所以很抱歉
I have no intention of resigning.
我没有要辞职的打算
Xiaoning.
筱柠
You're a smart girl.
你是一个聪明人
You know
你应该知道
why I chose you
我为什么放着更好的
over a better
合作方案不选
proposal.
而偏偏选择了你
The gift.
送你礼物
Dinner.
请你吃饭
The revision is easy,
简单几个字的修改
but I had to call you in.
却偏要把你喊到这儿来
Are my hints not obvious
我都暗示成这样了
enough to you?
你还装傻
Well, then I'll just have to be clear.
那我只能索性挑明
And the veil too.
头纱也要
Just the simple one
就女孩子都喜欢的那种
that girls love.
简约款就好
Yes.
对
I need it a bit of formal.
有点仪式感
I'll tell you the rest of
求婚的其他细节
the wedding proposal later.
回头我再跟你同步
Okay.
好
Don't look! Don't look!
不许看 不许看
Don't look!
不许看
What are you doing, Ji Yuheng?
干吗呀纪昱恒
You're taking advantage of me?
占我便宜
Taking advantage of you?
占你便宜
What am I taking advantage for?
我占你哪个便宜了
For work, of course.
当然是工作上的了
In life,
生活中
it's me who takes advantage.
是我占你便宜
We're
那生活中
so close in life.
咱们都这么亲密了
It's not a big deal if you take a tiny loss.
吃点亏也不算什么
Sometimes, loss is a blessing.
吃亏是福
Then I wish you to be blessed forever.
那我祝你福如东海
Well, I have to say,
那我是不是得祝你
same to you.
寿比南山啊
I've seen it.
看到了
You have?
你看到了
Ji Yuheng, you've seen it!
纪昱恒你都看到了